Camille Hansen-Theobald

Full Stack web developer leveraging education and performing arts background to build engaging user experiences. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from Columbia University, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, Node.js, React and responsive web design. Known as an inventive problem solver excited to develop intuitive apps, with a focus on mobile-first design and development. With each project, I hope to attract my audience with a pleasant user experience. I'm excited to use my skills as a valuable team-member, at a company I believe in, to build better experiences on the web.

camilleht@gmail.com

NEW YORK, NY

Portfolio:

https://camillenicolet.github.io/

code-with-camille/

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/camillehansen-theobald-a3530b16/

GITHUB:

github.com/camilleNicoleT

PROJECTS

INDUBITABLY — Seek and Hire for jobs by skill

https://tranquil-ocean-87497.herokuapp.com/

~Me and five developers built Indubitably out of the need for a straight forward job seeking app that cuts through the cover letter and straight to the skills needed. My responsibility was focused on the Front End logic and UI aspects. Use Node.js and Express.js to create a RESTful API, Handlebars.js as the templating engine. *Front End* MySQL and the Sequelize ORM for the database. *Backend*

MakiMaku — Dinner and a movie dating app

https://camillenicolet.github.io/MakiMaku/

~Me and four developers built MakiMaku to make a date at home more spontaneous but randomly selecting a film and dinner recipe for the user.

EXPERIENCE

American Musical and Dramatic Academy, New York City — Assistant to Student Affairs and Housing

MONTH 2009 - PRESENT

- ~Work with StarRez and CampusView web applications to organize student housing data, track disciplinary incidents and track communications
- ~Manage Resident Assistant student workers by overseeing their training and overall growth and development as RAs.
- ~Coordinate appealing and educational Residential events
- ~Design monthly bulletin boards for passive programming throughout the Residence Halls.

United Stations Radio Network, New York City — Writer

December 2016 - PRESENT

- ~Pitch new comedic bits each week based on current news topics then write them, edit and record by end of day.
- ~Voices for the newly written scripts to be produced immediately and released to clients
- ~Create new characters with a running theme that clients will want to have regularly on their show.
- ~Write and edit Children's Story Podcast "Detective Dexter"

Cieri Media, New York City — Producer and Host

December 2014 - August 2016

~Coordinate and research new video ideas for the NY Indie Film festival and

SKILLS

JavaScript

GraphQL

Node.Js

PWA

React

MongoDB

NODE.is

SQL

Express.js

jQuery

HTML

CSS

BootStrap

~Write and Host videos on the subject at hand.

EDUCATION

Columbia, New York — Certificate of Completion, Full-Stack Web Development

Dec 2021- May 2022

AMDA, New York — Musical Theater Performance

September 2007 - May 2009